Hello, and welcome back. We are going to benefit once again from
大家好 欢迎回来 我们将再次借助MATLAB
MATLAB to learn a few of the examples of different types of noise that we have
来学习几个实例 都是关于上一讲中不同类型的噪声的
learned in the previous video. Let us, first of all, as we already know
首先 正如我们所知道的那样
how to do that, load an image. This is one other image that comes with a
载入图像 这是另一个取自MATLAB包的图像
MATLAB packet. This in particular is a color image RGB.
特别地 这是一幅RGB彩色图像
So we are going to first transform it into a black and white image.
所以我们首先将它转换为黑白图像
We're basically only going to be paying attention to the luminance component of
我们基本上只会注意图像的亮度
the image. That's this operation that we see here.
这儿就是进行这个操作
Then we're going to add Gaussian noise, that's what we see here.
接着我加入高斯噪声  就是这所显示的
So Gaussian means we are going to add Gaussian noise to this image and that
“gaussian” 意味着我们将在图像中加入高斯噪声
Gaussian noise is going to have a variance of 2.
并且高斯噪声的方差为2
Then we're going to add salt and pepper noise with 2%,.
然后我们加入2%的椒盐噪声
meaning 2% of the pixels in the image I are going to be changed to either black
按照椒盐噪声的定义 这意味着
or white, according to the definition of, of salt and pepper noise.
图像 I 中2%的像素将转换为黑或白
And then we are actually going to add 20%
接着我们加入20%的椒盐噪声
So that's this image. Now, what we are going to do, is we are
就是这幅图像 现在我们要做的是
going to load all the images, the original color image, the black and
载入所有图像 原先的彩色图 黑白图
white version of that image, the Gaussian noise, the 2% salt and
高斯噪声图 2%椒盐噪声图
pepper noise, and the 20% salt and pepper noise.
和20%椒盐噪声图
So let's just see what happens. Once again, we are basically loading all
让我们来看看会发生什么 我们再一次载入所有图像
the images. Now, I'm going to move them so we can
现在我移动它们以使我们更好地观察
look at them better, but I think you managed to see some of
但是我想你已经能看到它们中的一部分了
that already. So there's a lot of images here.
这儿有许多图像
And, let's see first the original image. This is the RGB, the color of image that
让我们首先看看初始图像 这是RGB图像
we loaded first. I'm going to remove that so we don't have
就是那个我们最先载入的彩色图像 我将关闭它
so many images on the screen. Here is the original image.
这样屏幕上就不会有太多图像 这是初始图
Here is the result of finding the Gaussian noise.
这是加入高斯噪声后的图像
The first observation you can see is basically there is noise all around the
第一眼你就可以感觉到图像上基本都是噪声
image. So, this is Gaussian noise.
这就是高斯噪声
Every pixel has some noise according to the Gaussian distribution.
依据高斯分布 每个像素都会有一些噪声
Contrary to that, we see here that 2% salt and pepper noise.
而这的2%的椒盐噪声图与之形成反差
Some of the pixels of the image have been affected, only 2% of them.
图像中 只有2%的像素受到了影响
Now, once they are affected, they become either completely white or completely
正如我们所看到的 一旦它们受到影响 它们就变成完全的黑色或白色
we see what happens when we have 20% of noise.
最后 我们看到的是加入20%椒盐噪声的图像
So you see a lot of pixels that basically became either black or white.
你可以看到许多的像素变成了黑色或白色
Once again, compared to only 2%, and compared to the Gaussian noise, that is
再一次地 与2%的椒盐噪声图和所有像素都受影响的高斯噪声图比较
affecting all the pixels. And finally, then just look again at this nice
最后再一次看看原先完美的图像
original image. So these are different types of noise,
这就是不同类型的噪声
Gaussian noise and salt and pepper noise, and basically different densities of
高斯噪声和椒盐噪声以及不同密度的椒盐噪声
noise for salt and pepper. We could also have played with different
本来我们还可以演示拥有不同方差的高斯噪声
variances for the Gaussian noise, but I think that this is sufficient to
但是以上应该足以使你们理解各种类型的噪声了
Thank you very much and see you in the next video.
非常感谢大家 我们下个视频见